DENIS COUTO

Senior Systems and Cloud Engineer

+353 083 151 4346 Brazilian denis.couto@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/deniscouto/ | about.me/docouto







Infrastructure engineer and scripter with almost two decades in the field. Experienced in planning, deploying, support, maintenance, and technical delivery in enterprise environments.

Working on small business to large complex multinational environments using all sorts of solution stacks from Microsoft (On-Prem and Azure), VMware, Citrix, Redhat and others. PowerShell heavy user, able to leverage advanced features of the language.

Skills & Expertise

- Extensive knowledge of Microsoft Stack (onprem and Azure).
- Solid knowledge of PowerShell.
- Working knowledge in configuration/automation tools such as Bicep, Ansible and Terraform.
- Working knowledge of Linux administration (CentOS/Ubuntu).
- Good understanding of CI/CD, containers, orchestration tools such as Azure DevOps, Octopus Deploy, Docker and Kubernetes.

Certifications

Azure: DevOps Expert CCA-V: Citrix Certified Associate-Virtualization Azure: Administrator Associate CC-VAD-CC: Citrix CVAD Service on Citrix

MCSE: Cloud Platform and Infrastructure Cloud

Professional Experience

Citrix Systems, Dublin, Ireland

2018 - Present

Senior Escalation Engineer

Working in the EMEA Escalation team, I provide analysis of complex problems in a 24x7 follow the sun support environment.

In-Depth knowledge of Citrix DaaS and Citrix Cloud, leverage debugging techniques to manage high severity cases which can be politically or technically challenging daily.

Day to day goes through SysInternals tools, PowerShell, Splunk, Azure, code review on Sourcegraph and Bitbucket, memory dump analysis with WinDBG, trace analysis with Baregrep, engaging Engineering for further troubleshooting through Jira and Slack.

I delivered some training sessions to Frontline engineers on how to leverage PowerShell console during troubleshooting sessions with customers to act quickly and effectively while assessing the customer issue.

#Citrix #DaaS #Azure #Identity #Engineering #Debugging #Splunk #Powershell

Ergo Group, Dublin, Ireland

Level 3 Support Engineer

2015 - 2018

Working on escalation and on BAU tasks for several customers (Aercap, CIE, Goshawk, AerLingus, Dunbia and many others) managing a variety of products and services, such as: Windows Server (2008 to 2016), Linux (Ubuntu, CentOS), Azure, Office 365, Hyper-V, VMware ESXi, Netscaler, Xenapp, MS RDS, Exchange, System Center and others.

Also worked on a dedicated team for a single customer where beyond the daily operational tasks I had the opportunity to automate a series of tasks through PowerShell using functions and modules that helped to:

Finding details of servers combining data from AD, Solarwinds and VMware.

- Finding and gather details of SQL Server databases an SQL Server instances.
- Syncing employee's photos in Active Directory for later use in Skype and other platforms.
- Wrapping APIs to better integration between LOB applications.
- Backing up, encrypting SQL Databases and securely sharing with 3rd party vendor.

For this same customer I was responsible for their continuous deploy environment based on *Octopus Deploy*, orchestrating with a 3rd party vendor the deployment of their main application throughout Test/UAT/PROD environments and making sure those environments were in sync regarding their data.

I was also engaged on the planning phase to bring their custom intranet web site to Gitlab and enable their 3rd party vendor to be able to commit code and get it pushed to the appropriate environments, instead of doing screen sharing to deploy updates.

#Level3 #Virtualization #Azure #Powershell #Octopus #Elastic #Linux #Ansible

DoMore! Soluções em Produtividade, São Paulo, Brazil

2009 - 2015

Senior Microsoft Infrastructure Engineer

- Planning, deploying, and managing medium to large SharePoint farms and applications for companies like Odebrecht, Vale, PWC, Pfizer, Carrefour and others.
- Administering internal and cloud infrastructure running several Microsoft solutions such as Hyper-V,
 AD, WSUS, IIS, SharePoint (2007,2010, 2013), Office 365, SQL Server, Visual Studio Team Services.
- Automating SharePoint Installation and web sites deployment trough PowerShell.

#SharePoint #WebDevelopment #Powershell

Atento Brasil, São Paulo, Brazil

2006 - 2008

L3 Server Support Engineer

- Performing 3rd level support to Windows environment with more than 10.000 users and 12 locations nationwide.
- Managing VMware ESXi and Microsoft network products (AD, DNS, DHCP, WSUS), Exchange Server 2007 cluster with BlackBerry Integration Services.
- Performing changes on environment through change requests and working on support tickets.

#Level3 #Windows #Virtualization

SSI Consultoria, São Paulo, Brazil

2004 - 2006

Server Administrator

- Managing a Windows network environment including Active Directory, DNS, DHCP, RRAS and File Services.
- Administering SQL Server together with Visual Source Safe.
- Managing Linux (Red Hat) Iptables Firewall, Web Proxy with Squid and reports with SARG.

#SysAdmin #Windows #Linux #Firewall #Proxy #SCM

Education & Trainings

- Degree in Computer Networking Faculdade Eniac (São Paulo Brazil)
- VMware V6 Fast Track SureSkills (Ireland)
- Skype for Business Partner Technical Airlift *Microsoft* (Ireland)
- Implementing Microsoft Azure Infrastructure Solutions Global Knowledge (Ireland)